《黑衣人：全球追缉》
（巴黎 2016年）
天呐 我太讨厌巴黎了
God, do I hate Paris.
别担心 地球也许马上就毁灭了
Not to worry. Probably won't be around much longer.
（游客止步 禁止入内）
这一刻我已经等了很久了
I've been waiting a long time for this.
我想说的是…
I guess what… What I'm trying to say is,
- 莉莎 你愿意嫁… - 你们好
- Lisa, will you mar… - Bonjour.
我们是铁塔保安
We're with Tower security.
非常抱歉
We're terribly sorry,
但你们不应该来这里
but you're not supposed to be here.
- 抱歉 - 抱歉
- Sorry. - Sorry.
那么 她答应了吗
So? She say yes?
- 我还没求婚 - 他还没求婚
- I haven't asked yet. - He hasn't asked yet.
那真是太遗憾了 不是吗
Well, that's a terrible shame, isn't it?
因为你们看 那边闪烁的灯
Because, you see, that blinking light back there.
说明二号传送门遭到入侵
means there's been a breach in Portal 2.
也就是说 几分钟后
Which means, in just a few minutes,
全宇宙最邪恶的生物 蜂兽
the most vile creatures in the entire universe, the Hive,
将把我们所有人从里到外吃得一干二净
are gonna consume every last one of us from the inside out.
你们在说什么
I don't understand.
你们只要盯着这里看
All will be explained if you look right…
就懂了
here.
铁塔因修缮而关闭
The Tower was closed for repairs.
下去的时候向她求婚
Ask her on the way down.
这边请
This way, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
小心缝隙
Mind the gap.
好了 开始吧
Right. Shall we?
我们上
Let's do this.
（游客止步 禁止入内）
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
到地面后再向她求婚一次
Ask her again down on the ground.
- 你回来了 - 嗯
- There you are. - Yeah.
好了 我们再试一次吧
All right. Let's try this again, shall we?
现在怎么办
So, what's the play here?
我们以前经历过这种情况
We've been in this situation before.
我们从未对峙过蜂兽
We've never faced the Hive before.
他们也从未对峙过我们
They've never faced us.
记好了
Always remember,
宇宙总有办法
The universe has a way of leading you.
在恰当的时机
to where you're supposed to be.
将你引向应该去的地方
at the moment you're supposed to be there.
是啊 有时候宇宙也会搞错
Yeah, well, sometimes, the universe gets it wrong.
（布鲁克林 二十年前）
（你在这里）
（《时间简史 从大爆炸到黑洞》 史蒂芬·霍金著）
让我们动起来
"Let's have some action.
把屁股扭起来
I want some asses wiggling.
要有进步
I want some perfection."
去拿我的三号木杆
Get my three-wood.
- 麻利点 - 好好好
- Come on, let's go. - Okay, okay.
小心点
Careful.
天啊
Oh, my God!
- 天啊 宝贝 - 怎么了
- Oh, my God. Baby. - What?
根本不是动物
That wasn't no animal, okay?
是…是…
It was a… It was a…
我从没见过这样的东西
I ain't never seen nothing like that before.
像是一个生物
It was, like, a creature.
什么 哈洛德 快报警
What? Harold, call the police.
- 报什么 - 报警 快报警
- The who? - The police. Call the police!
这么快
That was fast.
晚上好 我们是动物管理局的
Good evening, folks. We're from Animal Control.
你说看到了奇怪的东西
You said you saw something?
是的 但我们还没打电话呢
Yeah. We haven't even called you yet.
我们有危险吗 它有狂犬病吗
Are we in any danger? Does it have like, rabies?
不像是普通的动物
That wasn't a regular animal.
- 像是… - 你见到的生物
- It was like… - The creature you saw was.
是一只来自仙女座II的无证塔伦特
an unlicensed Tarantian from Andromeda II.
非常稀有 非常危险
Very rare, very dangerous.
- 不好意思 你说什么 - 一只塔伦特 女士
- Sorry, what? - A Tarantian. Ma'am.
我知道 目前他看起来很可爱
No, I know. He looks cute now.
- 塔伦特 - 但是等到了青春期
- Tarantian? - But when they hit puberty,
他们就会变成真正的怪物
they turn into real monsters.
别害怕 没事的
Don't be scared. It's okay.
告诉我 屋里还有别人吗
Tell me, is there anyone else in the house?
只有我们的女儿 她在睡觉
Just our daughter. She's sleeping.
一只浣熊 没错 这就是你们的问题
A raccoon. Yeah, that's your problem, folks.
确保把垃圾桶的盖子盖紧了
So just go ahead and make sure those trash can lids are on nice and tight,
我们没来过这里
and we were never here.
也许我们应该去看看莫莉
Maybe we should go check on Molly.
你得离开这里
We've gotta get you out of here.
快来
Come on.
没事的
It's okay.
我是你的朋友 我叫莫莉 去吧
I'm your friend. I'm Molly. Go on.
莫莉
Molly.
Kabla nakshulin
Kabla nakshulin.
莫莉 你在每个领域都取得了优秀以上的成绩
Well, Molly, you've scored excellent or above in every area.
（联调局 纽约分部）
身体素质 演绎推理 逻辑
Fitness, deductive reasoning, logic,
武器训练
weapons training.
只有一个问题
Just one problem.
你没勾选
You didn't check a box.
选择想去的部门
For your preferred division.
每个人都得勾选
Everyone has to check a box.
我自己为没有框的部门
Yeah, I made my own box.
画了一个框
for the division that has no box.
你懂的 这个部门的人都穿着黑色套装
You know, the division where they wear black suits.
负责处理…
and deal with the guys from…
上面来的家伙
up there.
你是说会计部门吗
You mean, Accounting?
不 我是说…
No, like…
嗯 还是…
Yeah, still…
会计部门
Accounting.
这样应该就能解决
That should fix the glitch.
- 请记住 我们在乎 - 没问题了
- Remember, we care. - You're good to go.
请记住 我们在乎
And just remember, we care.
找到标着高级扩展功能的图标
Look for the icon marked advanced extensions.
- 好的 - 点击它
- Okay. - Click on it.
哪个图标 哪个 太多了…
Which icon? Which one? There's a bunch…
- 从左数第十三个图标 - 谁的左边
- Thirteenth icon from the left. - Whose left?
- 你的左边 - 抱歉
- Your left. - Oh, sorry.
- 我找到了 - 好 找到了吗
- I got it now. - Okay, got it?
嗯 找到了
Yeah, I got it.
（正在追踪新的异常物体 命名为2019-AMRJ）
你还在吗
Are you still there?
- 在吗 帮帮我 怎么回事 - 没事 没什么
- Hello? Help. What's going on? - Oh, no. Nothing.
我这边运行一个小小的诊断程序
Let me just run a little diagnostic on my end,
然后再回复你 不不不 用不了多久
and I will be right back to you. No, no, no, it won't take long.
很快的 好的
Not long at all. Okay.
怎么搞的
What the f…
- 令人费解 - 这是
- This is perplexing. - Is it?
这是
Is it?
外星人吗
A-l-i-e-n-s?
我不明白你为什么非得
I don't know why you always insist.
既小声又拆开说
on whispering and spelling that.
终于决定要露面了吧
Finally decided to show up, huh?
天呐
Oh, my God.
我只需要搞清楚轨迹 就能打入内部了
All I have to do is figure out trajectory, and I am in.
我回来了 好了 试试这个
I'm back. Okay, try this.
- 拔掉电源 再插回去 - 好的
- Unplug it, plug it back in. - Okay.
请记住 我们在乎
And remember, we care.
我得走了
I have to go.
吉米要回来找孩子们了
Jimmy's coming back to get the kids.
对
Yes.
好了 来看看现在你在哪儿
Okay. Let's see where you are now.
（国家宇航局）
欢迎回来 阿米塔奇教授
Welcome back, Professor Armitage.
你这个狡猾的家伙
You tricky one.
你应该不是流星吧
I don't think you're a meteor after all, are you?
不 我觉得你是未经许可的到来者
Nope, I think you are an unauthorized landing.
就是这个
This is it.
终于等到了
It's all happening.
稍后见 吉米
See you soon, Jimmy.
（世界新闻日报 外星人前任吉米说 「我会回来的 宝贝」）
就在这停 就在这停
Right here, right here.
就在这停
Right here.
请别停表
Please keep the meter running.
- 我加钱给你 - 什么
- I'll pay you extra. - What?
（危险 高压电围栏 五万伏）
对对对 拜托 吉米
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Come on, Jimmy.
你回地球干什么
What are you doing back on Earth?
这里是…这里是地球吗
This is… This is Earth?
我搞错了 伙计们 拜托
My bad, guys. Come on.
回总部跟O说去吧
Tell it to O back at HQ.
我只是想见我的孩子们
I just want to see my kids.
把这艘飞船弄走
Get this ship out of here.
我把这位赞波利安朋友带回去
I'll escort our Zamporian friend back.
- 别跟丢了 - 什么
- Don't lose them. - What?
- 我这就追 - 快追 快
- I'm on it. On it. - Go, go, go. Go.
他们把那个赞波利安人带回来了吗
Did they bring in that Zamporian yet?
比你早到了几分钟
Came in a couple of minutes ahead of you.
那家伙想借着英仙座流星雨的掩护溜进来
The guy tried to sneak in behind a Perseid meteor shower.
太业余了 我说得对吧
Amateur hour. Am I right?
千真万确
Right as rain.
不打幌子
Rain don't lie.
老天 还说什么业余
Sheesh, talk about amateur hour.
你不上报吗
You gonna call this in, or what?
黑色警报
Code Black.
未经许可的访客
Unauthorized visitor.
封锁协议倒计时
Lockdown protocol engaged.
三 二 一
in three, two, one.
好了 她为谁工作
All right, who's she working for?
她声称是独自工作
She claims to be working alone.
一个平民碰巧大摇大摆地
A random civilian simply waltzes in.
从大街上走进来了 我才不信
off the high street. I don't think so.
（联邦调查局 华盛顿外勤办事处 培训探员申请表 莫莉·莱特）
消除她的记忆
Neuralyze her.
不不不 不要
No, no, no. Don't.
我知道这东西是干什么的 拜托
I know what that thing is. Please.
等一下
Hang on. Hang on.
她有过经历
She had an experience.
它消除了我父母的记忆 却没消除我的
It erased my parents' memories, but it didn't take mine.
所以从小到大 所有人都说我疯了
So my whole life, everyone's called me crazy.
他们说我需要治疗
They said that I needed therapy,
好吧 我承认我确实需要
which, okay, admittedly, I did,
但不是因为这个
but not for this.
她真的黑进了哈勃望远镜
Did she really hack into the Hubble Telescope.
来观测仙女座II 而我们却没逮到她吗
to look at Andromeda II, and we didn't catch her?
如果是以前 我们还会聘用她
In the old days, we'd have hired her.
我花了差不多二十年时间找到你们
It took me 20 years to find you, plus or minus.
有几个人能这么说
How many people can say that?
我找到你们了
I found you.
你找到我们了 你证明了自己没疯
So you found us. You proved you're not crazy.
给你颁一枚正常人徽章 然后呢
You win the I'm Not Crazy badge. Now what?
- 我想加入 - 我们不招聘 只招募
- I want in. - We don't hire. We recruit.
那我想让你们招募我
Then I'd like to be recruited.
这样可不够
I'm going to need more.
不过你能给我一个说得过去的理由吗
But would you mind giving me one good reason?
因为我很聪明
Because I'm smart.
很有动力
I'm motivated.
我穿黑色很好看 我…
I look good in black. I'm…
很无趣
Boring me.
因为我完全没有个人生活
Because I have absolutely no life whatsoever.
我一无所有 没有狗 没有猫
I have nothing. I have no dog, no cat,
淡定不下来
definitely no chill.
没有任何值得留恋的事物
I have nothing that I couldn't happily walk away from,
所以我非常适合这份工作
which makes me perfect for this job.
你真是太可悲了
Well, you're certainly suitably tragic.
没有爱 没有人际关系
No love? No relationships?
那些只会分散你对重要的事的注意力
They just distract you from what's important.
是吗 那什么是重要的事
Really? And what's important?
宇宙的真谛
The truth of the universe.
我想知道一切
I wanna know everything.
我想知道宇宙的运作方式
I wanna know how it all works.
你真的认为黑色套装
You really think a black suit.
能解决你所有的问题吗
is going to solve all your problems?
不能 但你穿起来就非常好看
No, but it looks damn good on you.
这倒是真的
That's true.
（训练第一周 探员 莫莉·莱特）
（录用）
从现在起
From this moment,
你要遵从我们给你安排的身份
you will conform to the identity we give you.
你只能穿着黑衣人特勤队的服装
You will dress only in MIB Special Services attire.
你已经接受了黑衣人认可的技术
You have been trained in the use of MIB-sanctioned technology,
车辆及武器的培训
vehicles and weaponry.
任何情况下 你都不可以引人注目
You will not stand out in any way.
体制中再也没有你这个人
You are no longer part of the system.
你根本不存在
You do not exist.
结账 谢谢
Check, please.
我们凌驾于体制之上
We are above the system.
超越体制 我们就是体制
Over it, beyond it. We are them. We are they.
我们是黑衣人
We are the Men in Black.
黑衣「男人」吗
The "Men" in Black?
不 别提这个
Don't. Don't start.
我跟他们谈过
I've had the conversation.
他们似乎无法放弃这个名字
They didn't seem to be able to let it go.
这是个过程 依恋的问题吧
It's a process. Attachment issue, I think.
这是你的第一个任务
There's your first assignment.
好的 我什么能拿到…
Okay. When do I get my…
那叫记忆消除器
It's called a neuralyzer.
不是随便就能拿到的 要通过努力争取
And you don't just get it, you earn it.
你只是作为试用探员被录用了
You've been accepted for a probationary period.
好好表现 我们再考虑消除器的事
Impress me, and we'll see about the bzzz.
好吧
Okay.
（试用期 黑衣人伦敦分部）
你喜欢追求真相 不是吗 探员M
You're a fan of the truth, aren't you, Agent M?
我喜欢
I like it.
伦敦分部好像有麻烦了
I think we may have a problem in London.
（伦敦）
这酒还真是顺口
That is smooth.
继续上 好吗
Let's keep them coming, shall we?
再来一杯
Another round.
我只是想说我很喜欢这个地方
So can I just say how much I'm liking this place?
有条理 但又不会太古板
It's formal, but not too stuffy.
很传统 但却还是有范
Classic, but still kind of stylish.
很有《大开眼戒》的感觉
Makes it a very Eyes Wide Shut kind of vibe.
我说笑的
I'm kidding.
算是吧
Sort of.
或者只是致命的高风险赌博的效果
Or is it mostly just the lethal high-stakes gambling?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
你们看 王牌送上门 先生们
Would you look at that? Straight to the ace, gentlemen.
又是我
That's me again.
我们谈谈正事吧
Let's talk business, shall we?
我可以卖这东西
I can move this stuff.
我想大量进货 应该找谁
Who do I speak with about getting a whole lot more of it?
因为我想加入
Because I'm in.
你不能加入
You're not.
我有一条非常严格的政策
You see, I have a very strict.
「不得与黑衣人交易」
"no Men in Black" policy.
天呐
Oh, God.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
谁会想让那些混蛋进来插一脚
Who'd want those assholes coming in here?
黑衣人 要我说他们是黑衣蠢货
Men in Black. The Morons in Black, if you ask me.
一群傻逼 我没说错吧
What a bunch of dicks. Am I right?
一粒老鼠屎就能毁掉一锅汤…
All it takes is one bad apple to spoil any environment…
各位别动手
Stop it, guys.
我是黑衣人 你个切鲁败类
I am MIB, you Cerulian scum.
我要说 你这个小俱乐部烂透了
And FYI, your little club here sucks.
你要从实招来
You're gonna give me everything.
供应商 卖家 你的整个分销网
Suppliers, sellers, your whole network.
你的好运耗尽了
Your luck run out.
你死定了
You're already dead.
这里只有一个人有解药
Only one person here has the antidote.
艾米丽 亲爱的
Emily, sweetheart.
拜托 你要什么我都给你
Please, I'll… I'll give you whatever you want.
拜托 什么都行
Please. Anything you want.
什么都行吗
Anything I want?
开往伦敦的特快列车已到站
The express train to London has arrived.
我们将继续开往巴黎 斯德哥尔摩
With continuing service to Paris, Stockholm,
米兰 罗马 马德里
Milan, Rome, Madrid.
在更衣室逮到他
Caught him in the locker room.
我就知道那孩子对自己用了记忆消除器
I knew that kid was neuralyzing himself.
我跟他说 「用太多次会瞎的」
I told him, "Do that too much, and you'll go blind."
对吧
Right?
有人想来点零嘴吗
Who could go for a nosh?
我想来个熏牛肉三明治
I'd like a nice pastrami sandwich.
要加很多融化的奶酪
With lots of melted cheese.
来自纽约的特快列车即将到站
Now arriving, express train from New York.
最后一次通知 飞往猫眼星云的2112航班即将起飞
Last call for Flight 2112 to the Cat's Eye Nebula.
欢迎 探员M
Welcome, Agent M.
请前往新探员说明会报到
Please report to New Agent Orientation.
（踏上）
（处理中）
准许进入 探员M
Access granted, Agent M.
每小时一班 12号登机口
…every hour from Gate 12.
借过 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
（外星人监视系统）
总是出乎意料
It's never who you think it is.
不 这个完全说得通
Oh, no. That one makes sense.
找到我们的人就是你
So you're the one who found us.
是的
Yes, I am.
我是T 老大T
I'm T. High T.
你就是…
Yeah. You're…
- 我是这个马戏团的老大 - 嗯
- I run this little circus. - Yeah.
欢迎你 M
Welcome, M.
很高兴认识你 长官
It's nice to meet you, sir.
O告诉我新人值得期待
O told me to expect some great things.
- 你不会失望的 - 很好
- And great things shall you get. - Good.
往那边走
Right through there.
你好啊
Hi, you.
等等 等等 别碰他
Wait, wait, wait! Don't touch him!
天呐
Oh, God.
我抓到他了 你们…
I got him, I got him. You guys…
我抓到他了 我抓到他了
I got him. I got him.
（光年之旅 始于脚下 老大T）
（马拉喀什）
跳闸了
去修一下
那就去付电费
修一下 修一下
Change it, change it.
好了 伙计
All right, buddy.
来试试这个
All right. Drink this.
小心点 弄坏了就要付钱买
Careful. You break it, you buy it.
你们留着吧
Keep it. Keep it.
送你们了
On me.
我们要见女王
We need to see the queen.
好的
Yes.
有访客
You have visitors.
向女王禀报你们的来意
State your business with the queen.
我们要一个人死
We need someone to die.
仙女座II条约第6C条明确指出
As clearly stated in Section 6C of the Treaty of Andromeda II,
我们不杀加贝边人
we do not kill Jababians.
也不会参与谋杀行径
nor participate in the murder thereof.
没有商量余地
This is nonnegotiable.
好吧 有一点商量余地
Well, it's slightly negotiable.
早
Morning.
我想找一台又旧又破的废物机器
I'm in the market for a useless, old, broken-down machine.
你有吗
What do you got?
你别想惹我生气 H
You're not gonna get a rise out of me, H.
有红色跳格键的帝国打字机
It's the Imperial with the red tab.
别落后好吗
Do try to keep up.
谢谢你 查理
Thank you, Charlie.
这是以前的传送门站
That's the old portal depot.
第一次大型外星人移民的现场
Site of the First Great Alien Migration.
等等 埃菲尔是黑衣人探员吗
Wait, so Eiffel was an MIB agent?
首批探员之一
One of the first.
他帮助了很多来地球
He helped so many intergalactic refugees.
寻求庇护的星际难民
seeking protection here on Earth.
如果你仔细看
If you look closely,
就能看到我的祖父母也在照片中
you can see my grandma and my grandpa in that picture.
真美
So beautiful.
- 给你 亲爱的 - 谢谢
- Here you are, dear. - Thank you.
那家伙是怎么回事
What's up with that guy?
内尔琳恩
Nerlene!
抱歉
Sorry.
他实在是太诱人了
He's just so yummy.
- 他是谁 - H
- Who is he? - H.
这栋楼里最优秀的探员而已
Only the best agent in the building.
他曾经仅用他的智慧和七系原子枪
He saved the world once with nothing but his wits.
就拯救了世界
and a Series-7 De-Atomizer.
他拯救过世界吗
He saved the world?
从谁手上拯救的
From what?
蜂兽
The Hive.
伙计 帮我个忙
Hey, Guy, do me a favor.
- 帮我处理来电 - 乐意之至
- Handle my calls. - Oh, love to.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去做点调查
To do some homework.
马拉喀什发生了一起非常可怕的事件
An awful, terrible incident in Marrakesh.
北非办事处正在调查
The North Africa office is investigating.
至于其它事宜
And in other business,
H终于决定大驾光临了
H has decided to grace us with his presence after all.
很抱歉 长官
Apologies, sir.
我昨天工作到很晚 大家早上好
I was working late. Morning, everyone.
我也是 其实是在收拾你的烂摊子
So was I. Actually cleaning up after your mess.
谢谢你了
Thank you for that.
你应该瞧瞧我今天早上收拾的烂摊子
You should've seen the mess I was cleaning up this morning.
这完全是未经批准的行动 长官
It was a totally unsanctioned op, sir,
需要两支控制小队和一整支记忆消除小组
requiring two containment units and a full neuralyzer squad.
我觉得不是
I doubt that, right?
我更想从宏观的角度来看待这件事
I prefer to look at this from a macro point of view,
不要太纠结于细节
not get bogged in the details.
反正坏人死了 所以嘛
The bad guy's dead, so, you know.
请坐 最后一件事
Take a seat, please. One last item.
一位加贝边王室成员
A member of the Jababian royal family.
在前往半人马座A星途中要作停留
has a layover on his way to Centaurus A.
丑八怪万格斯
Vungus the Ugly.
继承了头衔
Inherited the title.
信不信由你 万格斯其实是个美男子
Believe it or not, Vungus here is the looker in the crowd.
全息影像总会让人重九斤
Holograms always add 10 pounds.
加贝边社会不允许某些言行失仪
Jababian society doesn't allow for certain indiscretions.
简而言之 他想玩得开心
In short, he wants to be shown a good time.
我们可以拒绝 但加贝边人的采矿船
We could say no, but Jababian mining vessels.
会把我们碾成银河系的星尘
would grind us into galactic dust.
长官 这有点讽刺 想想我们过去
Some irony there, sir, if you think that we used to, uh,
是保护地球免受宇宙中的人渣侵扰
protect the Earth from the scum of the universe.
现在看起来我们是在保护人渣
Now it seems we're protecting the scum.
事实上 正是因为如此 这事很适合你
Actually, that's why it would be right up your street.
你的那杯茶 H
Your cup of tea, H.
我认识万格斯 他其实不怎么喝茶
Well, I know Vungus. He doesn't really drink tea.
他更爱伏特加 龙舌兰
He prefers vodka, tequila,
免洗洗手液 有时候三种一起喝
hand sanitizer, sometimes all at once.
有一回我们在曼谷醒来 被铐在一匹马上…
There is one time, we woke up in Bangkok, handcuffed to a horse…
- H - 安静
- H? - Pipe down.
怎么了 抱歉 真心抱歉
What? Sorry. Sincere apologies.
你来当他的保护人
You will be his chaperone.
实际上 他特别要求找你
In fact, he specifically asked for you.
好吧 没问题 希望我们最后
Okay. Absolutely, hopefully we don't end up.
不会再被铐在马上
handcuffed to a horse again, heh.
拜托
Please.
午夜前我会送他回家
I'll have him home by midnight.
那就太好了 真是好孩子
Good boy. If you will.
「那就太好了 真是好孩子」
"Good boy. If you will."
我想他说的是「好男儿」
"Good man, " I think he said.
要让爸爸开心是吗
Keep Daddy happy, yeah?
是啊 我们就是这么铁
Yeah. We're like this.
你把爸比照顾得真好
You look after Papi so well.
你是不是很嫉妒
You're so jealous, aren't you?
爸比漂亮的小男孩
Papi's little fancy boy.
你也想要个爸比
You wish you had a papi.
他们乘坐交通工具到达…
They came in on transportation…
你好
Hello.
糟糕
Oops.
- 抱歉 - 你好
- Sorry. - Hi.
我是醒着的 没事
Nope, I'm awake. It's all right.
只是在赶着做我的每日冥想
Just catching up on my daily meditation.
我一直想尝试
I have been meaning to try that.
我有读过 它能显著地提高
I read that it dramatically improves.
线粒体的能量产生
mitochondrial energy production.
是的 是的 绝对可以
Yep, yep. It… It absolutely does.
我的线粒体能量已经爆棚了
My mitochondrial energy's through the roof.
- 我们见过吗 - 没有 我是探员M
- Have we met before? - No. Agent M.
我听说你今晚要去见万格斯
I heard you were on the Vungus meet tonight,
我想为你提供帮助
and I wanted to offer assistance.
我是个加贝边迷妹
I'm a bit of a Jababian wonk.
语言 文化 政治 时尚
Language, culture, politics, fashion.
总之 我编写了一份档案供你阅读
Anyways, I compiled a dossier for you to read.
档案 我喜欢好档案
A dossier. I love a good dossier.
问题是…你去打听一下
The thing is… Ask around.
我是单干的 大家都知道
I work alone. Ask anyone around here.
你知道加贝边人是能预测未知的读心者吗
Did you know that Jababians are claircognizant empaths,
也就是说他们可以读你的大脑
which means they can basically read your mind?
还有你的牌
And your cards.
- 不过他们会露出马脚 - 什么马脚
- Well, they do have a tell. - What's that?
他们胳膊内侧的皮下斑点会改变颜色
Subdermal spots on the underside of their arms change color.
很高兴知道这个 但是
Good to know. But,
谢谢你的提议 我不需要
thank you for your offer. I'm good.
好的 明白
Okay. Message understood.
我不打扰你…
I will leave you to your…
冥想了
meditation.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道你的马脚是什么吗
Do you know what your tell is?
你冥想的时候会打呼噜
You snore when you meditate.
其实转念一想 也许我需要一个后援
Actually, on second thought, maybe I could use some backup.
我在想 这次行动我可以负责监控外围
So I was thinking, for the op, I can take the perimeter,
- 你负责接近万格斯 - 很好
- and you make the approach to Vungus. - Yes, good.
问题是 在这一家俱乐部里
The thing is, with this particular club,
大家都想按自己的喜好来
everybody just wants to do their own thing.
外星人想看起来像人类
You know, the aliens wanna look like humans,
人类想看起来像外星人
humans wanna look like aliens,
所以我们可能需要放松一点
so we may need to loosen up a bit.
或许我们先把领带解掉
Maybe we lose the tie first, yeah?
解开几粒扣子 别看着那么死板
Pop a couple of buttons and not look so stiff.
我们不想广而告之自己的身份
We don't want to advertise our profession,
如果你明白我意思的话
if you know what I mean.
「快看 是黑衣人 外星人 趴下」
"Look! It's the Men in Black. Aliens, get down!"
- 不要那样 - 我明白
- Don't do that. - Yeah, I get it.
明白吗 很好 非常好 我看起来怎么样
Yeah? Good. Great. Perfect. How about me? How do I look?
我觉得…
I would just, uh…
- 你介意我… - 什么
- Do you mind if I… - What?
过来
Coming in.
关键在于拿捏介于俱乐部休闲风
Think as it's a fine line between club casual.
和地球上最悲惨男人之间的感觉
and the saddest man on Earth.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们走吧
Shall we?
我以为我们已经到了
I thought that we were here.
是到了
We are.
特别来宾入口
Entrance for special guests.
踩油门吧 弗雷迪
Step on it, would you, Freddie?
没问题 H
You got it, H.
好吧 这可没想到
Yeah, okay. Wasn't expecting that.
万格斯大驾光临
The Vungus among us!
H氢弹
H-Bomb!
万哥 万哥
V-go! V-go!
瞧瞧你 你瘦了
Look at you. You've lost weight.
你的头发怎么了
What have you done to your hair?
你换了发型 看起来好棒
You've changed it. Looks fantastic.
- 我… - 我差点没认出来你
- I… - I barely recognize you.
抱歉 M 这是万格斯
Sorry. M, this is Vungus.
万格斯 这是M
Vungus, M.
你好 M
Hello, M.
很高兴认识你
So nice to meet you.
我听说了你的好多事
I've heard a lot about you.
当然了 我只挑好话说
Highly redacted, of course.
真会说话 他说…
Such a charmer. He says…
他觉得你很辣
he thinks you're hot.
他觉得我很什么 不好意思
He thinks I'm what? Sorry?
当然这只是大概的翻译
It's a rough translation, of course.
可能用加贝边语说更好
Probably works better on Ja… Jababia,
但你明白的 因为你的加贝边语很流利
but you know that, since you speak fluent Jababian.
当然 我只是想找合适的词来表达
Of course. I was just trying to find the words to articulate.
你有多不可思议地光彩夺目
how incredibly eye-catching you yourself are.
他正是如此
Well, that he is.
M对加贝边无所不知
M knows everything there's to know about Jababia.
我不会说自己「无所不知」
Well, I wouldn't say "everything."
学无止境
There's always more to learn.
这是她的癖好
It's like a fetish.
你这话说得好像和性有关似的
Okay, that implies something sexual.
- 绝对不是的 - 不 就是的
- It's definitely not. - No, it is.
你总是「加贝边这个」
It's always like, "Oh, Jababia this,
「加贝边那个 加贝边 加贝边」
Jababia that, Jababia, Jababia, Jababia!"
亲爱的
Yeah, baby!
看吧 我就知道你们俩合得来
See, I knew the two of you would hit it off.
去跳舞吧 M很爱跳舞
Have a dance, okay? M loves to dance.
她跳舞很厉害 我去拿点酒
She's a wonderful dancer. I'll get some drinks.
你还是喜欢蔓越莓伏特加吗
You're still a vodka cranberry guy?
你知道的
You know it.
好 好
Okay. Okay.
M 来吧
M, please.
来坐在万格斯旁边
Come, sit next to Vungus.
我保证我不会咬人的
I promise, I don't bite.
好吧 等我一小会儿
Okay, just give me one sec.
给我们四杯蔓越莓伏特加
Get us four vodka cranberries.
没事的 我来买单
It's all right. I'll get this one.
用公司的卡结账
Put it on the company card.
给你个小提示 什么都用公款
Little tip, expense everything.
有个小问题 没什么大不了的
Quick question, no big deal.
你是要给我和万格斯拉皮条吗
Are you pimping me out to Vungus?
什么 不
What? No.
你怎么会有这种想法
What the hell would give you that… impression?
你好啊
Hello.
我不知道 因为那个吧
I don't know. That?
最好不要看那个
Better not look at that.
如果你想让我当外星人诱饵
If you wanna use me as alien bait,
下次先让我知道 好吗
just let me know next time, okay?
我不想被欺骗
I don't like to be lied to.
是吗 就像假装是一个
Really? What, like pretending to be an expert.
你并不擅长领域的专家吗
in something you're not?
如果你还没意识到 干这行就是撒谎
In case you haven't noticed, we're in the lying business.
- 是吗 - 加贝边人很难搞
- Are we? - Jababians are prickly.
我们想让他们开心 好吗
We want them to be happy, okay?
这样他们就不会把我们和地球一起毁灭
So they don't destroy our planet and everything on it.
这就是任务
And that is the mission.
- 如果你不能接受… - 我能接受任务
- If you're not down with… - I'm down with the mission,
但我不要和加贝边人乱搞
but I'm not fornicating with the Jababian.
我没有要你那么做
That's not what I asked you to do.
你这次来待多久 兄弟
So how long you here for, buddy?
万格斯明天回家
Vungus go home tomorrow.
明天
Tomorrow?
那我们最好尽情享受 对吧
We better make it a good one, huh?
我来是有话要说 H 我们得聊聊
I came to talk, H. We need to speak.
别聊了 来吧 我想看你跳舞
Talky, shmalky. Come on, I want to see you dance.
来吧 来吧 我知道这是你喜欢的节奏
Come on. Come on, I know, I know this is your jam.
快过来 M 过来
Get out here. M, come on.
不了 我就坐着吧 我喜欢坐着跳
Oh, no, I'm just gonna… I like to butt-dance.
有件事我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you about something.
如果你想谈贝鲁特那晚的话
If it's about that night in Beirut,
照片我已经删了 我保证
I deleted the photos. Promise.
不是 不是贝鲁特
No, not Beirut. Just…
- 探员H - 什么事
- H? - Yeah?
十二点方向
Twelve o'clock.
你说的太对了 时间还早呢
You're damn right it is. Night is young.
听我说 探员H
Listen to me, H.
我是认真的
This is serious.
你是万格斯唯一能信任的人
You're the only one that Vungus can trust.
我也信任你
Well, feeling's mutual.
- 你怎么了 - 没怎么
- What happened to you? - Nothing.
你怎么突然这么严肃
Why are you so serious all of a sudden?
- 放轻松 - H
- Relax. - H.
你没事吧 伙计
You all right, buddy?
怎么了 你看起来不太好
What's wrong? You don't look so good.
- 你没事吧 - 万格斯感觉不舒服
- You okay? - Vungus not feel so good.
蔓越莓伏特加确实劲很大
Vodka cranberry sure pack a punch.
我们送他上车 离开这里
Let's get his car and get him out of here.
- 好的 - 没问题
- Yeah. - Yup. All right.
好了 送你回去睡觉
Okay. Get you off to bed.
我们送你上车 好了
Let's get you in here. All right.
好了 伙计 进去吧
There you are, buddy. In you go.
小心头 好的 好了
Watch your head. Okay. All right.
好好睡一觉 明白吗
Now, sleep it off, okay?
明早再跟你聊 多喝水
I'll speak to you in the morning. Hydrate.
- 我们是不是应该上报 - 天呐 不行
- Shouldn't we call it in? - Oh, God, no.
填文件简直是噩梦
The paperwork is a nightmare.
但万格斯看起来不太好
But Vungus didn't look too good.
他之前看起来就不太好 但是…
He didn't look too good before, but…
相信我 我见过他更糟的样子
Trust me, I've seen him way worse.
有一次在伊斯坦布尔…
This one time in Istanbul…
救救我
Help me.
- 黑衣人 不许动 - 趴在地上
- MIB. Freeze! - On the ground.
- 手掌向下 - 手举起来
- Palms down. - Hands up.
- 手举起来 - 手掌向下
- Hands up. - Palms down.
你想用哪个 我两个都行
Which do you want to go with? I'm fine with either.
我只是觉得未来我们得
I just think in the future we're gonna have to.
统一指令 你想用手掌向下吗
come up with something consistent. You want palms down?
如果你不介意的话
If you don't mind.
- 手掌向下 - 手掌向下
- Palms down. - Palms down.
很好
Good.
搞什么
What the…
这可不妙
That is not good.
快跑
Run!
M
M!
他们来了
They are coming!
油箱盖 快
Petrol cap. Go.
我们需要更强的火力 侧视镜
We need more firepower. Side-view mirror.
你想让我怎么办 拿这个砸他们吗
What do you want me to do, throw it at them?
这我可没见过
I haven't seen that before.
我觉得这个不管用
I don't think this is doing anything.
拜托
Come on.
排气管 快
Exhaust pipe. Go!
来吧
Come on!
这还差不多
Now this is more like it.
没错
Right.
快点
Hurry!
去救万格斯 我掩护你
Go to Vungus. I'll cover you.
H 来搭把手
H! A little help here!
不行 别叫H
No. Not H.
他变了
He has changed.
我能感觉到
I could feel it.
我必须确认
I have to know…
能否信任你
if I can trust you.
这下我生气了
Now I'm pissed off.
把这个藏起来
Hide this.
黑衣人内部不太对劲
Something is wrong in Men in Black.
什么 万格斯 这是什么
What? Vungus, what is this?
只有这东西能保护你
It's the only thing that can protect you.
来吧
Come on!
你们时髦的舞步去哪了
Where's your fancy dance moves now?
搞什么
What the…
盯紧了 不安全
Keep your eyes on. It's not safe.
盯紧了 盯紧了
Eyes on! Eyes on!
两个目标
Two targets!
他怎么样
How is he?
他死了
He's gone.
各位 退后一点 好吗
Guys, back up a little bit, all right?
你超越了自我了 伙计
Outdone yourself here, mate.
- 做得好 做得好 - 谢谢
- Well done. Well done. - Thank you.
跟我说说 发生什么了
Fill me in. What happened, huh?
很明显 我们遇袭了 C
We were attacked, clearly, C.
- 好吧 - 对方不知是什么东西
- Right. - By I don't know what.
嫌犯 这是他们徒手造成的伤害
The suspects, they did this with their bare hands.
他们将固体变成液体
They turned solid into liquid,
- 然后又变回去了 - 什么
- then back again. - What?
- 她怎么在这里 - 她…
- Why's she here? - She…
- 她要… - 她要…
- She is… - She is…
为你讲解犯罪现场
walking you through the crime scene.
不 不行 她是试用探员
No, no. She is a probationary agent,
所以她不能出现在这里 明白吗
so she is not here at all, okay?
很明显她现在就在这里
I think you'll find that she clearly is here.
因为我能看到她
because I can see her.
- 支持你了 - 谢谢
- Backing you up. - Thank you.
只是一种说法 不过好吧
A figure of speech, but fine.
你惹上大麻烦了 天呐
You are in so much trouble, oh, my God.
你只有一个任务 非常简单的任务
You had one job. You had one very simple job:
带这个蜥蜴混球出去喝几杯
To take some lizard slimeball out for a few drinks.
- 就这么简单 - 不是「蜥蜴混球」
- That was it. - Not a "lizard slimeball."
- 他是我的朋友 - 不对
- A friend of mine. - Oh, no.
抱歉 我说错了
Yeah. Sorry about that.
他生前是个爬虫混球
He was a reptilian slimeball,
现在因你而死
he is now dead because of you.
他死的时候谁跟他在一起
Who was with him when he died?
- 我 - 谁
- I was. - Who?
好吧 他有没有说什么
Okay, good. And did he say anything.
能够解释他被杀的理由的话
that might explain why he was killed?
什么都行 快说
Anything at all? Come on.
没有 什么也没说
No. Not a thing.
- 我重新概括一下 - 没必要
- So just to recap… - No point.
加贝边皇室的一名高阶成员
A high-ranking member of the Jababian royal family.
在你们的保护下死了
dies on your watch,
袭击者你们识别不出来
murdered by assailants that you can't identify,
谋杀的原因你们也说不上来
for reasons that you cannot begin to fathom.
是这样吧
Is that about right?
你一开口我就自动屏蔽了 不知道
I switched off the moment you started talking. I don't know.
你怎么还不滚
Now why don't you bugger off.
好吧 伙计 谢谢
Okay, mate. Thank you.
- 嗯 - 这就滚
- Yeah. - I'll piss off,
- 回办事处 - 你属于那里
- Back to the office. - Where you belong.
去跟老大T谈谈
To have a word with High T,
这次他可救不了你了
who will not save you this time.
我们会没事的 好吗 别担心
We'll be fine. Okay? Don't worry.
这个…我们会没事的
This is… We'll be fine.
好吗
Yeah?
是的 是的 明白
Yes. Yes. Understood.
是的 的确
Yeah… Indeed.
是的
Yes.
是的 是的
Yes. Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
（打败蜂兽 仅用他们的智慧和七系原子枪）
我向你保证 我们将以
Let me assure you, we will deal with this.
最严厉的措辞处理此事
in the strongest possible terms.
加贝边人想要你们的脑袋
The Jababians want your heads.
字面意义 两颗头 用外交包裹邮寄
Quite literally. Both heads, sent by diplomatic pouch.
好吧 这个…
Okay, um, ahem…
早上好 长官
Morning, sir.
我拿来了你要的法医报告
I have the forensics report that you asked for.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就有问题了
Well, this is troubling.
问题大了
Very troubling.
这是我们的嫌犯
These are our suspects.
名叫幻影双煞的物种
A species called Dyadnum.
来自天龙座的二元星系
From a binary star system in the constellation Draco.
天龙座 那是蜂兽的领地
Draco, that's Hive territory.
整个区域多年前就沦陷了
The entire sector fell years ago.
幻影双煞的DNA
The Dyads' DNA…
充斥着蜂兽的变异基因
are riddled with Hive mutations.
我们都知道 蜂兽不仅摧毁敌人
As we all know, the Hive doesn't just destroy their enemies,
还会将其吸收
they subsume them.
从内部彻底掌控
Take them over from within.
不管这两人是谁 他们都成为蜂兽的一部分了
Whoever these two were, they're part of the Hive now.
是的 但只是杀一个加贝边皇室
Yes, but why would the Hive send them all this way.
蜂兽为什么要如此大费周章
to kill a Jababian royal?
你比任何人都更了解万格斯
You knew Vungus better than anyone.
他有没有说过自己为什么来这里
Did he indicate why he was here?
他想从我们这里得到什么吗
Did he want something from us?
没有 他看起来挺正常挺开心的
No, he seemed pretty normal, happy.
长官 整件事都一团糟 就是个烂摊子
Sir. This whole thing is a fiasco. It's a farrago.
这么重大的失败
And a failure of this magnitude.
需要立即启用
requires immediate involvement of…
第十三条
Article 13.
别犯浑了 谁会说「烂摊子」这种词
Don't be a dick. Who says "farrago"?
第十三条是什么
What is Article 13?
立即停职 接着消除记忆
Immediate termination, followed by neuralyzation.
- 等一下 - 等等
- Wait a second. - Wait.
- 不行 - 你们这些人只会这样处理问题吗
- No. - Is that you people's answer to everything?
快收起来
Put that away!
- 摘掉眼镜 - 长官 你不能这么做
- Glasses off. - Sir, you can't.
给我一个不这么做的理由
Give me one good reason why not.
因为这是…
Because it's…
我们之前谈过的
what we were talking about.
- 因为… - 因为…
- Because… - Because…
如果你消除我们的记忆 就永远无法得知真相
if you erase us, you will never know the truth.
- 真相 - 长官 他们显然在拖延时间
- The truth. - Come on, sir, they're obviously stalling.
- 你下令我就动手 - 收起来
- Say the word. I'll do it. - Put it away.
M 继续 解释一下
M, go ahead. Explain yourself.
长官
Well, sir…
如果你认真想想 仔细想想
if you think about it, really think about it…
万格斯
Vungus…
有几个人知道他来了
how many people really knew that he was here?
只有这个房间里的人
The people in this room.
大概还有十几个高级探员
And perhaps a dozen high-level agents.
如果只有这些人知道万格斯会去哪里
If those were the only people that knew where Vungus would be,
并且我们假设万格斯没有
and we assume that Vungus didn't leak.
把自己的位置泄露给杀手
his own location to the killers,
这是不是意味着泄密的人
doesn't that mean that it was someone…
在黑衣人内部
inside MIB?
有内奸 长官 就在我们之间
A mole, sir, inside these very walls.
长官 他们很显然是现编的
Sir, they're abviously making this up as they go along.
胡说什么？「有内奸」？
What are you talking about? "A mole"?
组织成立以来从未有过泄密事件 还说「有内奸」
In the whole history of the company, there's never been a leak."A mole."
这话像是内奸才会说的
That sounds like something a mole would say.
- 别胡扯了 - 内奸经典语录
- Don't be absurd. - Classic mole talk.
听起来像是内奸初级教学
Sounds like Mole 101.
够了
Enough.
如果我们已经被渗透了
If we've been compromised,
那这个星球上的每位居民都处于危险之中
it puts every citizen on this planet,
人类和外星人都是
both human and alien, at risk.
- C - 长官
- C. - Sir.
追踪这两个杀手
Track down these killers.
找到杀手 我们就能揪出内奸
Find the killers, we find the mole.
- 好的 长官 - 解散
- Will do, sir. - Dismissed.
M 看起来你的确像自己说的那样聪明
M, it appears you're as sharp as advertised.
和C一起查这件案子
Work the case with C.
让武器部门研发能够
Get Weapons Department started on something.
干掉幻影双煞的武器
that can neutralize these Dyads.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
她的确很聪明 长官
Sharp indeed she is, sir.
我想你打算让我监督这个案子 对吗
I assume you'll want me overseeing the case? Sort of…
H 我再也不会为你打掩护了
I'm finished covering for you, H.
这个案子你需要我 长官
You need me on this case, sir.
我以前跟蜂兽打过交道 记得吗
I've dealt with the Hive before. Remember?
仅用我的智慧和我的七系…
With nothing but my wits and my Series 7…
不 是这个人跟蜂兽打过交道
No. He dealt with the Hive before.
而我不知道这个人现在跑去哪儿了
And I don't know where the hell he has gone!
我过去真心认为你可以领导这个地方
I actually used to think you could lead this place.
我看错你了
I was wrong about you.
没你的事了
We're done here.
这是命令
That's an order.
你没有看错我 长官
Look, you weren't wrong about me, sir.
你曾经在我身上看到的东西 仍旧在那
You saw something in me once. It's still there.
让你失望了 我向你道歉
And I apologize for letting you down.
再给我一次机会 我会弥补过错的 我保证
Give me another chance and I'll fix this. I promise you.
我觉得不仅仅是个刀片
I don't think it's just a blade.
看起来上面还有毒
Looks like it carries some poison.
我知道你什么意思 等等
I know what you're talking about. Wait.
不好意思 兄弟 老大T决定了 他想要我
Sorry, mate. High T decided he wants me.
- 负责此案 - 等等 什么 不好意思 我不信
- to run point on this one. - Wait. What? Sorry, I don't believe you.
我也和你一样不满
I don't like it any better than you,
但他一直说什么就靠我了
but he kept going on about relying on me,
需要我们的顶尖探员 之类的话
needing our top agent, that sort of thing.
不是我说了算 你找他说去
I don't make the rules. Take it up with him.
M 他希望你跟我一起调查此案
M, he's keen for you to shadow me on this one.
他说 「向最优秀的人学习」
"Learn from the best, " he said.
如果你愿意的话 来点在职培训
Little on-the-job training, if you will.
怎么样 来吧
Yeah? Come on.
- 你要跟他走还是留下来 - 我跟他走
- Are you going or you staying? - Yeah, I'll go.
- 好吧… - 好的
- Yeah, alright… - Okay.
- 来吧 - H
- Come on. - H?
多谢帮忙
Thanks for that.
我真受不了你
I'm sick of you.
好吧
Okay.
- 所以实际情况是什么 - 你来告诉我
- So what's the actual truth? - Well, you tell me.
因为对讨厌撒谎的人来说 你的表现太棒了
Because for someone who hates lying, that was incredible.
- 我没有… - 刚刚多刺激啊
- I wasn't… - Come on, it was electric up there.
我们互相配合 你一句我一句
The way we played off each other, back and forth.
- 我是临场发挥 - 黑衣人有内奸
- I was riffing. - A mole inside the MIB.
天啊 太机智了 要是我自己能想出这一招就好了
God. It's genius. I wish I thought of it myself.
我发现了一种可能性
And I discovered a possible truth.
想想看 这能解释很多事
I mean, think about it. It would explain a lot.
目前为止你掌握了些什么
So what have you got so far?
我准备对这种物质做分子解构
I was about to run a molecular deconstruction on the substance.
然后与所有毒素进行交叉对比
and cross-reference with all toxins.
- 好主意 - 简单的科学手段
- Good idea. - Just a little science.
我就不会这样做
I wouldn't do that.
我知道这是什么
I know what that is.
是啊 它杀死了一个136公斤的加贝边人
Yeah. That killed a 300-pound Jababian,
我就不会拿它来玩
so I wouldn't get recreational with it.
这是泽福斯 极高纯度
That's Zephos, pure grade.
剂量掌握不好能立刻致死
The wrong amount will kill you instantly.
但恰好的剂量能让你在摩纳哥的夜店
Right amount will keep you dancing shirtless.
脱掉上衣 狂舞整整十七个小时
on a nightclub in Monaco for about 17 hours straight.
信息量太大了 总是那么大的信息量
So much information. Always so much information.
反正我就是这么听说的 全世界只有一个地方的人
It's what I've heard anyway. There's only one place in the world.
知道怎么调制它 我们走吧
where they know how to mix it. Let's go.
你来吗 世界可不会拯救自己
You coming? World's not gonna save itself.
你是说你需要我去拯救世界吗
Are you saying that you need me to save the world?
我也这么觉得
Thought so.
（马拉喀什）
在这里经常会看到这个
You'll see that a lot around here.
是克罗穆联标签
It's a Cromulian tag.
在他们的星系中 这是希望和湮灭的标志
In their galaxy, a symbol for hope or annihilation.
至于到底是什么还存在争议
There's still some debate around what exactly.
实际上 是和谐
Actually, it's harmony.
但在地球上 它意味着我们进入了黑衣人安全港
But on Earth, it means we're entering an MIB safe haven.
- 你怎么知道的 - 手册里有说明
- How do you know? - It's in the handbook.
不要全盘相信你读到的一切
Don't believe everything you read.
- 那是我的工作 - 那我的工作是什么
- That is my job. - And my job is what?
无所事事 然后闭上嘴吗
Hang out here and shut up?
是的 闭嘴 那就是你的工作
Yes. Shut up. That's your job.
看看这是谁 纳斯尔
Well, look who it is. Nasr.
你清楚规矩的 公众场所禁止出现外星技术
You know the rules: no visible alien tech anywhere on the street.
把摩托车遮起来 否则我要给你开罚单了
Cover the bike up before I have to give you a ticket.
H 真是你吗
H? It is really you?
当然是我了 不然还能是谁
Of course it's me. Who else could it be?
- 巴萨姆 你好 - H 你好
- Hey, Bassam. - Hi, H.
纳斯尔说你死了
Nasr said you were dead.
什么 我…我没有说过
What? I… I never said that.
你说过 他在撒谎
You did. He's lying.
放…
Get…
- 那是… - 为什么说我死了
- That's… - And why would I be dead?
巴萨姆误解了
Bassam misunderstood.
我们听说你和瑞莎分手了
We heard that you and Riza had split up.
瑞莎 那是谁
Riza. Who's that?
那不重要
It's not important.
人类 还是…
Human or…
- 那不重要 - 我只是好奇
- Doesn't matter. - I'm just curious.
跨物种是什么样的 所以…
how it works between species, so…
非常不重要 只是我一个老朋友 所以…
Very unimportant. Old friend of mine, so…
你的老朋友掌管着星系中最大的犯罪组织
Who runs the biggest criminal syndicate in the galaxy.
还是一位十分成功的女商人
Who is a very successful businesswoman.
我喜欢女商人
I love a businesswoman.
好吧 我们为什么要谈这个
Okay, why are we talking about this?
太令人悲伤了 你们俩特别般配
So sad. You made a lovely couple.
谢谢你 但这种事很正常
Okay thank you very much. But these things happen.
你说 「那个神经病会割断他喉咙」
You said, "That psycho's gonna slit his throat."
不好意思 失陪一下
Excuse us for one moment.
是你说的 不是我 你难道没有…
Your words, not mine. Don't you…
你跟那个人交往过 似乎有利益冲突啊
You dated this person? Seems like a conflict of interest.
你知晓我的私人生活才叫利益冲突
Conflict of interest for you to know my private life.
是的 我也不想知道
Yeah, sure. I'd prefer not to.
够了 听着
That's enough. Listen.
别再暴揍他了
Stop beating the hell out of him.
- 就是 - 把这东西遮好
- Yeah. - Keep this thing covered up.
- 没问题 一定做到 - 谢谢
- Absolutely. Will do. - Thank you.
不会再犯错了
Won't happen again.
很高兴认识你们
Nice to meet you both.
- 好 - 好
- Yes. - Yeah.
什么事
What?
从夜店外的监控录像调出来的
Pulled this from the surveillance camera outside the club.
你站在那 搞得我很不爽
Standing there, making me feel uncomfortable.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
这个你拿给T看了吗
Have you shown this to T?
你说所有事都要先告诉你
You said everything goes through you.
是的 所有事都要先告诉我 很好
Yes, everything does go through me. Good.
我会给他看的 你继续
I'll show him. Go on.
我的天啊
Goodness me.
老天
Oh, boy.
麻烦来了
Here comes trouble.
我喜欢麻烦
I like trouble.
你在想我正在想的事吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
打给瑞莎
Call Riza.
到了 就是这里
Here. This is it.
看起来像是有几天了
Looks like a couple days' worth.
没人出来取过
No one's been out to collect.
有人吗
Hello?
再上前一步 我就把你的刘海液化了 小白脸
One more step and I'll liquefy your bangs, pretty boy.
- 别紧张 别紧张 - 好了
- Easy, easy. - Okay.
- 我们不想惹任何麻烦 - 别动
- We don't want any trouble. - Do not move.
看看你
Look at you.
我们该叫你什么 老兄
What do we call you, sport?
你们不能叫我「老兄」
"Sport" is not what you call me.
它是什么
What is it?
- 「它」 他才对 - 抱歉
- "It"? He. - Sorry.
为什么要问该叫我什么
Why would you call me anything?
小兵没有姓名 我们就是小兵
Pawns don't have names. We're pawns.
好吧 那就叫「兵兵」吧
Okay."Pawny, " then.
这里发生什么了
What happened here?
我们开了场最棒的派对
We had the best party.
侃爷到场了 发布了一张新专辑
Kanye showed up and dropped a whole new album.
是他最得意的作品之一 你自己看看
It was some of his best work. Look around!
明显是我们被袭击了
We got our asses kicked!
女王陛下
My queen!
她死了
She's gone.
我再也不会侍奉他人 我发誓
I'll never serve another. I swear it.
我将用短剑刺入
I'll plunge my dagger.
自己的身体 就像这样 贯穿所有的重要脏器
into my own body, like this, through all my vital organs,
然后就这样 等着黑暗带走我
and then leave it until the dark takes me.
你不会真的打算这么做吧
You're not gonna actually go through with this, are you?
听着 失去了女王的小兵 只是一个小兵
Listen. A queen's pawn without a queen is just a pawn.
毫无价值
A nothing.
我必须以最痛苦的方式
I must end my own life.
结束自己的生命
in the most painful way possible.
别阻止我
Don't stop me.
生存几率 零
Chance of survival: zero.
- 你觉得我们应该阻止他吗 - 马上就动手了
- Do you think we should stop him? - Gonna do it.
我想看看他会不会做到底
Kinda wanna see if he goes through with it.
- 不好意思 你们说什么 - 什么都没说
- Sorry, what did you say? - Nothing at all.
你知道吗 我的确说话了
You know what? I did say something.
- 你说了吗 - 是的 他是证人
- You did? - Yeah. He's a witness.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我觉得她不会希望你
You know, I don't think that she would want you to,
真的做到底 说真的
you know, go through with it, honestly.
你是谁 你怎么知道女王心中所想
Who are you to know what a queen would or wouldn't want?
你是一位女王吗
Are you a queen?
某种程度上来说所有女人都是女王
Well, to the extent that all women are, yes,
但不是 我不是女王
but, no, no, I'm not a queen.
但你知道她是什么吗 她是一位探员
You know what she is, though, is an agent.
「探员」
"Agent"?
- 那是一个头衔吗 - 是的
- Is that a title? - It is a title.
一个象征着卓越地位的头衔
A title of great eminence and stature.
M是一位探员
M here is an agent.
一位没有小兵的探员 你懂我意思吧
An agent without a pawn, if you see my meaning.
我还没想过这点
I never thought of this,
但是也许致敬亡者最好的方式
but maybe the best way to honor the dead.
- 就是继续活下去 - 没错
- is to go on living. - Yes.
我向你献上永恒的忠诚 M探员
I pledge loyalty eternal to you, Agent M.
不不 我对臣子不感兴趣
No, no, no. I'm not interested in a subject.
太迟了 说完了 我已经献上了忠诚
Too late. It's done. I already pledged the loyalty.
真希望你能早点说不要
Wish you'd said "no, no, no" before.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
如果你在我之前逝去
And if you should die before I,
我发誓将以最痛苦的方式
I promise to end my own life…
「结束自己的生命」
"In the most painful way possible."
是的 我不喜欢你
Yeah. Ha. I don't like you.
我们走吧
Let's go.
夫人
My lady?
别这样 我们会相处得很愉快的
Come on. We'll have a fun time.
- 好吧 - 太好了
- Fine. - Yes!
H 有件事我应该告诉你
H, there's something that I've been meaning to tell you about.
- 我一直想告诉你 - 什么
- I've been wanting to tell you… - Yeah?
- 这个 哪去了 - 你是说这个
- …about it. Where is it? - You mean this?
- 你从我这偷走的 - 从你那偷走
- You stole it from me? - Stole it from you?
我是取回你从犯罪现场偷走的证据
I recovered evidence you stole from a crime scene.
万格斯让我把它藏好 我不知道该信任谁
Vungus told me to hide it and I couldn't trust anyone.
你是说 你听万格斯的话
You're telling me you listened to Vungus,
你信任万格斯 却不信任你的搭档
you trusted Vungus instead of your partner,
一位资深探员
a senior agent?
总的来说 是的
In a word, yes.
H 说到探员
H, speaking of agents…
过来
Come on.
他们为什么会在这里
Why would they be here?
要么这里要举办一场我们不知道的颁奖典礼
There's either an award show we're not aware of.
要么是我们有大麻烦了
or we're in deep shit.
谢谢 我要你封锁每一条街道
Thank you. I need you to close every street,
每一道拱门和下水道
every archway and every sewer now.
拉近那边那个摄像头
Come in closer on that body cam there, please.
- 再近一点 - 有谁可以跟我解释一下
- A bit more. - Could someone please explain to me.
这到底是怎么回事吗
what the hell is going on?
长官 这个话题比较敏感
Sir, slightly sensitive subject.
所以最好不要声张
Thought it best to keep it quiet.
- 再拉近一点 - C 借一步说话
- A bit further in, please. - C, a word.
好的 不许放任何人逃离麦地那市 懂吗
Absolutely. No one leaves the Medina, all right?
这太荒谬了
This… This is nonsense.
抛开你的个人情感而言
Despite your personal feelings,
H是有史以来最棒的黑衣人探员之一
H is one of the best agents ever to wear this suit.
他曾经是有史以来最棒的黑衣人探员之一
No, he was one of the best agents to wear this suit.
但是从蜂兽那件事之后他就不一样了 你看
He hasn't been the same since the Hive. Look. Look.
我的线人称
My sources say that Vungus stole it.
万格斯将其从加贝边作战部高级研究所偷走
from the Jababian War Department Advanced Research Division.
并带到了这里
and brought it here.
而你一直瞒着我 瞒了多久了
And you kept this from me? For how long?
- 解释一下你的行为 - 解释我的行为
- Explain yourself. - Oh, explain myself?
长官 不管这东西是什么
Sir, whatever that thing is,
之前在你办公室时 它在M和H身上
M and H had it in your office,
而你放走了他们 长官
and you let them go, sir.
无意冒犯 但是你放走了他们
With all due respect, you let them go.
- 继续吧 - 是 长官
- Carry on. - Yes, sir.
- C 还有 - 长官
- And, C. - Sir?
直接带他们来见我
Bring them straight to me.
无论那东西是什么 万格斯不惜一死保护它
Whatever that thing is, Vungus died to protect it.
他把它给了我 为了不让它落到他们手上
He gave it to me so it wouldn't go to them.
- 长官 - H 听我说
- Yes, sir. - H, listen to me.
这不是我下的命令
This isn't my operation.
尽快离开那里 到安全的地方再向我汇报
Get out of there. Get safe. Then report.
- M可能是对的 - 你 每十分钟我要听到一次汇报
- M may be right. - You, I want sitreps every 10 minutes.
黑衣人里可能有内奸
There could be a mole in the Men in Black.
好 拿着这个 我去引开他们
All right. Take this. I'll draw them away.
二十分钟后 中央广场见
I'll meet you at the main square in 20.
快走
Go.
各位 这也太巧了
Hey, guys, what are the odds?
纳斯尔 我要借用你的摩托车
Nasr! I need to borrow your bike.
好的 只要是借不是偷
As long as it is to borrow, not steal.
当然了 快点
Yes. Of course. Quick.
- 快 - 巴萨姆
- Come on. - Bassam!
- 好的 油门 刹车 - 水
- Okay, accelerator, brake. - Water.
- 外面非常热 - 你想得真周到
- Very hot out there. - That's very thoughtful of you.
这个应该很简单吧
This is all pretty straightforward, yeah?
是的 确实非常简单 是的
Yes. Very straightforward, indeed. Yes, yes.
就跟骑普通的摩托车一样
Just like riding a bike.
好的 那就好
Okay, cool.
抱歉
Sorry.
这跟骑普通的摩托车一点都不一样
Well, this is nothing like riding a bike at all.
快 上来
Quick, jump on!
抓紧了
Hold on tight.
靠
Shit!
坚持住 兵兵
Hold on, Pawny!
坚持住
Hold on!
等等我
Wait for me!
谢了
Thanks!
真不敢相信这招居然能行
I can't believe that actually worked.
- H - 怎么了
- Hey, H? - Yeah?
对了 戴眼镜
Right. Glasses.
大家好 你们能看着我这里吗
Hi, everyone. If you could all look right here.
开你的
Just drive.
快闪开
Move! Go!
天啊
Oh, boy.
你觉得呢 按红色按钮怎么样
What do you think? Press the red button?
我觉得这是超光速引擎
I think it's hyperdrive.
不 我觉得超光速引擎是蓝色按钮
No, I think hyperdrive is blue.
有的时候人得相信自己的直觉
Sometimes you have to trust your gut.
我的直觉 不是你的
My gut, not yours!
拜托谁随便按个按钮吧
Somebody press something!
把他们甩掉了
Lost the tail.
我说什么来着 超光速引擎
What'd I tell you, huh? Hyperdrive.
- 是是 好的 - 相信自己的直觉
- Yeah, yeah. Okay. - Trust your gut. Trust your gut.
天啊 我讨厌沙子
Oh, God, I hate sand.
红色按钮太酷炫了
The red button was awesome!
我们再按一次红色按钮吧
Let's press the red button again.
它在干什么
What's it doing?
移动
Moving.
这是什么东西
What? What is that thing?
看到核心了吗
See the core?
看到它持续释放的对流能量
How it keeps emitting convective energy.
是如何穿梭在光球层的了吗
across the interior of the photosphere?
是啊 我都看见了
Yeah, yeah. No, I see all of it.
看到了光球层
I see the… the photosphere bit.
好吧 嘘
Okay, yeah. Shh.
那些是热核爆炸
Those are thermonuclear explosions.
等等 什么意思 这是炸弹之类的东西吗
Wait, what? What does that mean? Like a bomb or something?
我认为我们看到的是一颗被超压缩的恒星
I think what we're looking at is a super compressed star.
根据这个色温来看
And by the color temperature,
我觉得这是一颗蓝巨星
I'd say it's a blue giant.
按一下这个按钮 我们瞧瞧它的威力
Let's press the button. Let's see what this does.
你提议我们拿一颗被武器化的恒星取乐吗
Are you suggesting we try a weaponized star for fun?
为了科学和取乐
Well, for science and fun.
- 这两项倒是不冲突 好吧 - 是吧
- The two aren't mutually exclusive. Okay. - I know.
的确 没有比这里更合适的地方了
Yeah, there is no better place.
他们都把这里称之为空白之地了
They don't call it the Empty Quarter for nothing.
对 所以我才这么提议的 快
Yes! That's why I made the suggestion. Go.
那就用千分之一的威力吧 你觉得呢
At just.001? What do you think?
好 从最低档位开始
Yeah. Just start off slow.
- 按下去吧 - 好
- Press the button. - Okay.
要不往上推几档
Maybe ratchet it up a few notches,
调高一点…
a little higher…
这还是最低档位
That was the low setting?
你觉得会有人注意到之前没有这个吗
Do we think anyone's gonna notice that wasn't there before?
长官 他们逃走了
Sir, they got away.
我想 更恰当的说法是
I believe the appropriate phrase is…
你把他们跟丢了
you lost them.
长官 我要说的是
Well, I put it to you, sir…
- 他们有帮手 - 也许吧
- that they had help. - Probably.
但是我了解H
But I know H.
不管他在做什么 都是有理由的
Whatever he's doing, there's a reason.
为什么你一直袒护他
Why do you keep protecting him?
到底怎样你才能明白
What is it going to take?
我在保护这个机构
I am protecting this institution.
从谁手中保护 我吗
From what? From me?
你是在质疑我的忠诚吗 长官
Are you questioning my loyalty, sir?
最起码是质疑你的判断力
At the very least, your judgment.
还有什么事吗 探员C
Is there anything else, Agent C?
- 没有 长官 - 很好
- No, sir. - Good.
那么请你出去好吗
Then would you kindly leave?
万格斯知道这玩意威力有多大 对吗
Vungus knew how powerful that thing was, right?
他知道这可以毁灭整个世界 而他交给了你
He knew it could destroy worlds, and he gave it to you.
我不能理解 你和他才刚认识
I don't understand. Someone he only just met.
他为什么要这么做
Why would he do that?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许他信任我
Maybe he trusted me.
我不怀疑你大致的可靠性
I'm not gonna doubt your general trustworthiness,
但是我可在万格斯母亲的葬礼上唱过歌
but, I mean, I sang at Vungus' mother's funeral.
补充一点 唱得还挺好听
Quite beautifully, I might add.
我们了解彼此的一切
We knew everything about one another.
我很确定他信任我
I mean, hey, I'm pretty sure he trusted me.
好吧 H 如果你一定要知道
Okay, H, if you must know…
他说你变了
he said that you'd changed.
我已经厌烦听到「你变了」这种陈词滥调了
I'm getting sick of hearing this "you've changed" crap.
我还是几年前的我
I'm the same person I was years ago.
你是想说你一直都是这样的吗
You meant to tell me you've always been this way?
哪样
What way?
有点笨拙
Vaguely inept.
傲慢 鲁莽
Arrogant. Reckless.
- 我还有遗漏吗 - 好吧 好吧
- Did I miss anything? - Okay, yeah. Hey, look.
傲慢 鲁莽 真会说话
Arrogant and reckless. Well, That's just nice.
也许我有的时候是这样
Maybe I am a few of those things occasionally,
但是我的工作是拯救地球 这就是我要做的
but guess what, my job is saving the planet, and that's what I do.
我也做得很好 只要我在拯救世界
I do a good job at it. While that's still happening,
规定就是 没有规定
the rules are: there are no rules.
那也算个规定
Well, that's a rule.
该死的 好了 谁都不许动
Damn it. All right, nobody move!
- 放下 毛球 - 谁都不许动
- Drop it, hairball! - Nobody move.
- 巴萨姆 你怎么来了 - 喝饱了吧 H
- Bassam. How'd you get here? - Feeling hydrated, H?
我还从来没洗过澡呢
Never had a bath before.
- 光是身上的泥就洗掉了两斤 - 天呐 我们还喝了
- Lost 2 pounds in dirt alone. - God, we drank from that.
天呐 我就觉得有一股活胡子的味道
Oh, God, I thought it tasted like a living beard.
好吧
Okay, um…
巴萨姆 听我说好吗
Bassam, listen, all right, mate?
讲讲理
Let's be sensible.
你不知道自己拿的是什么东西 所以…
I don't think you know what you're dealing with, so…
不 我当然知道
Oh, no, I definitely do.
所以她才会出个高价
Which is why she's gonna pay so much for it.
- 不 等等 - 不不不
- No, wait. Wait, wait! - No, no, no!
生活愉快 笨蛋们
Have a nice life, bozos!
干得漂亮 H
Great job, H.
兵兵 能麻烦你请她把扭力扳手递给我吗
Pawny, can you ask her to pass me the torque wrench?
她有名字也有头衔 你很清楚
She has a name and a title, and you know that.
夫人 那个混蛋跟你要扭力扳手
My lady, the jackass wants a torque wrench.
兵兵 麻烦你告诉他他越快恢复
Pawny, will you tell him the sooner he restores power.
驱动控制台的动力 我就能越快搞清楚
to my drive console, the sooner I can figure out.
- 怎么修好程序 - 夫人说了
- how to program it? - My lady says.
你是个毫无用处 因为自己的轻信
you're a cloth-brained ass-clown whose gullible idiocy.
让整个星球陷入危机的混蛋
has threatened the very existence of the planet.
她没这么说好吗
You know what, she didn't say that. All right?
你这个棋盘上最没用的小东西
You worst piece on the chess board.
- 她说了 - 一个字也没有
- She said that. - Didn't say any of it.
但我是这么想的 一个字都不差
Yeah, but I was thinking it. Actually, every single word.
你说得很好 谢谢
You make a really good point. Thank you.
麻烦你告诉你家夫人动力恢复了
If you'll tell your lady she now has power.
夫人 那个混蛋说动力恢复了
The jackass says, my lady, that you have power.
- 能替我谢谢他吗 - 不是吧
- Can you thank him? - Really?
冷冷地客套一下就行
But in a cold, kind of polite way.
瞪他一眼也是可以的
You can even put a glare on it.
你看着办吧 我相信你
Just play around with it. I trust you.
夫人说谢谢
My lady says thank you.
我知道他要带武器去哪 也知道怎么弄回来
I know where the weapon's going and how to get it back.
- 夫人 - 这次我来 我听着呢
- My lady? - I got this one. I'm listening.
巴萨姆只认识一个真正的买家
Bassam has only one real buyer:
瑞莎·斯塔夫罗斯
Riza Stavros.
瑞莎 跟你交往过的那个瑞莎吗
Riza? The Riza that you went out with?
那个星际外星武器商瑞莎
The intergalactic, alien arms-dealer Riza?
让我稍微倒带一下
I'm gonna hop back in for a second.
你跟瑞莎·斯塔夫罗斯交往过 那个死亡商人
You dated Riza Stavros, the Merchant of Death?
谋杀之母
The Mother of Murder?
- 她是挺辣的 - 我们初遇时
- She's pretty hot. - Okay, I didn't know.
我并不知道她是军火商
she was an arms dealer when we met.
而且我当时因为她的女性心机和
And I was distracted by her feminine wiles.
醉人的美分了神
and her intoxicating beauty.
再说了 我们对身份不感兴趣
And besides, we weren't interested in labels.
我们是被对方的心吸引了
We were interested in our hearts.
要是心里有爱也是罪 那就处我死刑吧
If having a big, old heart is a crime, then shoot me.
先别动手
Not yet.
需要动手的时候你会让我来的 对吧
You'll let me know, though, right?
不是吧
But really?
你还「心里有爱」
Your "big, old heart"?
- 怎么了 - 就是…
- What? - It's just…
很好笑 是吗
Well, it… It's funny, is it?
「心里有爱」
"My big, old heart."
- 真蠢 - 谁会这么说话啊 大笨蛋
- So stupid. - Who talks like that? Ha-ha-ha. Big, old doofus.
你从没谈过恋爱 对吗
You've never been in love, have you?
没有嘲笑你的意思 我是真的好奇
I'm not making fun. I'm genuinely asking.
你从来没有为激情放弃过逻辑吗
You've never once abandoned logic for passion?
搞什么啊 《恋恋笔记本》续集吗 我是没看过
What is this? The sequel to The Notebook? I never saw it,
不过我觉得那电影扯的就是这种故事
but I assume it's a lot of this type of nonsense.
对 我没谈过 激情不稳定
No, I haven't. Passion is unstable,
- 逻辑才是永恒 - 是吗
- and logic is constant. - Is that right?
是的 生理吸引力不过是
Yeah. Physical attraction is nothing more.
大脑中的化学反应
than chemical reactions in your brain.
不可信赖 它们不是真的
Can't trust them. They're not real.
难道整个宇宙不都是化学反应组成的吗
Isn't the whole universe a chemical reaction?
我觉得宇宙还是挺值得信赖的
Pretty sure you can trust that.
感觉挺真实的
Feels pretty real.
这话其实还蛮深刻的
That's actually kind of deep.
应该可以了
Well, that should do it.
启动吧
Power her up.
谢谢
Thank you.
兵兵 换个地方
Pawny. Not there.
我就能跳这么远
That's as far as I could jump.
其实还能跳高点 但是我觉得高点更尴尬
I could jump higher, but it would've been more awkward.
够了
Okay, enough.
开始了
Here we go.
瞧瞧
And look at that.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我了解瑞莎 虽说她是死亡商人
I know Riza. She may be the Merchant of Death,
但她却有一个弱点
but she does have one weakness.
准备好当英雄了吗 小家伙
Ready to be a hero, little guy?
让我当什么都行
Pretty open to anything.
很好 因为我们要去那不勒斯了
Good, because we're going to Naples.
去瑞莎的来者必死武装要塞吗
To Riza's Fortified Fortress of For Sure Death?
（瑞莎的来者必死武装要塞）
别开枪 别开枪
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
真不好意思
I'm so sorry.
我们改天再继续好吗 我又来了一个客人
Can we do this another day? I have another visitor.
- 没问题 - 好吗
- Absolutely. - Yeah?
谢谢
Thank you.
再见
Au revoir.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
卢卡
Luca.
- 想我了吗 - 没有
- Did you miss me? - No.
H
H.
我知道你为什么来
I know why you're here.
你怎么穿了条粉裤子
Why are you wearing pink trousers?
最近好吗
So how have you been?
好久不见了 分手最不好的就是
It's been a while, huh? That's the tough thing about breakups,
会同时失去朋友
is the friendships you lose.
我们以前多要好 不是吗
We had some good times, though, didn't we?
我想也许是我和瑞莎要好吧
Riza and I had good times, I guess.
你只是在背后默默跟着
You just lurked in the background a bit.
她是不是很美
Wonderful, isn't she?
我最喜欢
I just love.
又蠢又美的小东西
dumb, beautiful creatures.
真令人怀念 不是吗
Well, this is familiar, isn't it?
那么
So…
黑衣人终于把你开除了吗
MIB finally showed you the door, eh?
其实是我自己主动退出的
Showed myself out, actually.
有些人生来注定自由自在
Some horses are born to roam free.
还有人注定中枪 你来干什么
And others just get shot. What are you doing here?
我想来看看你 给你带了礼物
I wanted to see you. And I brought you something.
我知道喜欢特殊的宠物
I know how you like special pets,
所以我带了求和礼物给你
so I brought you a peace offering.
喵 喵
Meow, meow.
汪 汪 诸如此类
Bark, woof, et cetera, et cetera.
我喜欢
I like it.
他真是丑到可爱了 不是吗
He is cute in an ugly sort of way, isn't he?
这个物种的最后一只
The last of his kind.
你总是这么了解我的心 不是吗
You always did know the way to my heart, didn't you?
你总是能让我心跳加速
You always knew how to make mine beat that little bit faster.
什么记忆消除器也没法让我忘了这段对话
Not a neuralyzer in the world could make me forget that.
其实我本来还挺期待
I was actually looking forward.
看我的枪把你打成马蜂窝 接着就看到
to seeing my guns tear you to pieces, then I saw.
你那张完美的小脸 然后我就…
that perfect little face of yours, and…
我必须要知道
I had to know.
知道什么
Know what?
我要知道真相
I want to know the truth.
是真感情吗
Was this ever real?
我们之间
This?
你和我 是真感情吗
You, me? Was it?
这下有好戏看了
This'll be good.
是吗
Was it?
我从一开始就知道你是谁
I knew who you were from the start.
我的工作就是赢得你的信任
My job was to gain your trust.
等到时机成熟
and take you down.
一举拿下你 这就是真相
when the opportunity came. That's the truth.
我还是把耳机关掉吧
Gotta turn my earpiece off for this.
天呐 闭嘴行吗
God, shut up.
- 什么 - 不是 抱歉
- What? - No, I'm sorry.
我是在和我的内心对话
It's what I say to my heart…
就像脑海里还有另一个声音和我争吵
when it's like a voice inside my head.
我理解
I know.
这种事我无法假装
I couldn't fake that.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没事的
It's okay.
不 我是说谢谢你
No, but thank you for…
让我能够释怀
for giving me closure.
谁都有需要释怀的时候
We all need some… Some closure from time to time.
- 把他带出去 - 什么 等等 不
- Get him out of here. - What? Wait, no. Hey.
等等 我也需要释怀
Wait. I need some closure too.
- 我的感受怎么办 - H 给你个小建议
- What about my feelings? - H, here's a tip for you.
下次你要送求和礼物的时候
Next time you bring a peace offering,
不要选我拿到史上
don't make it the same day I come into possession.
最强武器的那天
of the most powerful weapon ever created.
这两件事没有任何关联
This has nothing to do with that.
我都不知道你拿到了什么武器
I didn't know you had a weapon.
完全没有关联 只是巧合
It's a separate thing. A coincidence.
完全是巧合 我真的不知道她拿到武器了
Total coincidence. Didn't know she had a weapon.
你知道她拿到武器了吗
Did you know that she has a weapon?
带他去船上
Take him to the boat.
好了 行 行
All right. Okay, okay, okay.
伙计们 要我说还挺顺利的
Fellas, I think that went pretty well.
看来我们以后要常见面了
Looks like we'll be seeing a lot more of each other.
好了
Okay.
好了 好了
Okay, okay, okay.
塞巴斯蒂安 亲爱的
Sebastian, darling.
你想不想足不出户
How would you like to be able to destroy.
就能摧毁整个太阳系
entire solar systems without leaving your home?
- 兵兵 - 嗯 我看到了
- Pawny? - Yeah, I see it.
瞧瞧这个 搞定了 M
Would you look at that. Good to go, M.
好了 兵兵 就看你的了
Okay, Pawny, it's all on you now.
这种压力对我不是很有帮助
Okay, that kind of pressure is not constructive.
事情很简单 亲爱的 你是要还是不要
It's very simple, darling. Do you want it or not?
不 我只有一个 塞巴斯蒂安
No, I only have one, Sebastian,
而且很快就会卖出去
and I won't have that for long.
不 我只给你五秒钟
No, I'm gonna give you five seconds.
干得漂亮
Perfectly done.
我回头再打给你
I'm going to call you back.
糟了 糟了 完蛋了
Crap. Oh, crap. Oh, crap.
看你那小短腿
Look at your little legs.
居然跑这么快
You are so fast.
看看你跑步的样子
Why, look at you run.
你跑得真快
You're so fast!
等等 我来了 我来了
Wait, I'm coming. I'm coming.
你不许再逃跑了 你好啊
Now, you don't run away again. Oh, hello.
我还以为
And here I thought…
H是单干的
H worked alone.
我真傻
Silly me.
你真惨
Poor you.
确实花了一段时间让他接受我
It's been a steep learning curve, yeah.
这个吗 这是一把短管卡其格歼灭者
Oh, that? That's a snub-nosed Karzig annihilator.
你知道人类被它击中会有什么后果吗
Do you know what that does to a human body?
它会让你由内而外地沸腾
It boils you from the inside out.
真好
Cute.
你知道兵兵会对
Do you know what a Pawny does.
暴虐成性的外星人武器贩子做什么吗
to sadistic alien arms-dealers?
不知道 亲爱的 告诉我什么是兵兵
No, honey. Tell me what a Pawny is.
我就是兵兵 你这个神经病
I'm a Pawny, you psycho!
看来形势逆转了
Looks like the tables have turned.
接得真准
That was an incredible catch.
感觉好极了
That felt good.
M
M.
M 别担心 别担心 这都是计划好的
M, don't worry. Don't worry. It's all part of the plan.
H 你的妄想症一点都没见好
Well, H, you always have been rather delusional.
求和礼物
Peace offering.
杀了他们
Kill them.
先杀他 多折磨一会
Start with him and make it hurt.
不 你没必要这样做
No! You don't have to do this.
把我放下 你这个塔伦特恶棍
Put me down, you Tarantian thug.
等等 你说他是塔伦特
Wait. Did you say "Tarantian"?
- 是的 - 没错 夫人 他说了
- Yes. - Yes, my lady, he did.
只要是跟杀人有关的事 他们就特别执着
They tend to be very single-minded when it comes to killing.
他们的大脑只有开心果那么大
Brains the size of a pistachio nut.
小声点
Okay, shh.
你这是帮倒忙
You're not helping.
你见到的生物是一只来自仙女座II的
The creature you saw was an unlicensed Tarantian.
无证塔伦特
from Andromeda II.
塔伦特
Tarantian?
我认识一个塔伦特
I know a Tarantian.
我以前遇到过
I met one once.
我帮了他
I helped him.
Kabla nakshulin
Kabla nakshulin.
什么
What?
Kabla nakshulin
Kabla nakshulin?
- 她说的那句 - 你怎么会知道
- What she said. - How do you know that?
因为他是这么跟我说的
Because he said it to me.
莫莉
Molly?
是我
Yes.
莫莉 你们在玩我吗 不是吧
Molly? Are you shitting me? Really?
现在是谁有妄想症
Who's delusional now?
是你吗
It's you?
你长大了
You've grown.
我也是
I mean, me too.
把盒子给她
Give her the box.
卢卡 你不能这样
Luca, you can't do this.
我对你不好吗
Haven't I been good to you?
我让你随心所欲地杀人
I've let you kill anyone you wanted.
别这样
Come on.
不行吗
No?
给我盒子
The box.
谢谢你
Thank you.
对了 你改变了我的人生
You changed my life, by the way.
问一下
Quickly.
Kabla nakshulin是什么意思
Kabla nakshulin, what does it mean?
意思是
It means:
「有一天 我会用你能想象的最恐怖的方法」
"One day, I'll kill whoever you choose.
「杀掉任何你想杀的人」
in the most gruesome way imaginable."
或许我们先把她关在这里
Or maybe we just keep her here for a moment.
等我们商量好行动计划再说
until he and I can discuss a plan of action.
H 你还好吗
H? H, are you okay?
我很好
I'm good.
刚刚真刺激
That was… That was a rush.
没错 还特别痛苦
Yeah, and incredibly painful.
- 是的 - 很显然
- Yeah. - Pretty sure the plan.
- 这个计划漏洞百出 - 是啊
- went wrong in every conceivable way. - Yeah, well…
你叫莫莉 是吗
So, uh, it's Molly, huh?
不应该让你知道的
You're not supposed to know that.
好吧 太晚了 我已经知道了
Well, too late. I know it now.
公平起见 只能告诉你我的名字了
Guess it's only fair that you know mine.
- 我不想知道 - 我要告诉你
- I don't wanna know yours. - I'm gonna tell you.
- 好吧 - 准备好了吗
- Okay. - You ready?
霍雷肖
Horatio.
- 你不叫这个 - 确实不是
- It is not. - It's not.
我叫亨利
It's Henry.
嗯 你看上去就像叫亨利的
Yeah, you look like a Henry.
- 很好 我就叫这个 - 我叫史蒂夫
- Good. It's all I've got. - I'm Steve.
史蒂夫 我记得你说小兵没有名字
Steve? I thought you said Pawns didn't have names.
确实没有 我只是觉得被忽略了
We don't. I was just feeling left out.
史蒂夫
Steve.
怎么回事
What?
这可不妙
That is not cool.
我不喜欢地面变成这样
I don't like what the earth is doing now.
不不不
No, no, no.
Kabla nakshulin
Kabla nakshulin!
试试无妨
It was worth a try.
为了蜂兽 我们必须拿到那件武器
We must have the weapon, for the Hive.
不行 不知你们有没有听说过
No. I don't know if you've heard,
但我们是黑衣人
but we are the Men in Black.
黑衣男女
The Men and Women in Black.
说得好
Nice save.
如果你们觉得我们会直接把它交出来
If you think we'll just hand this over,
那就大错特错了
you've got another think coming.
你们不知道自己在跟什么人打交道
You don't know who you're dealing with.
我们保护地球
See, we protect the Earth.
也就是说保护地球上的一切
And that means everyone and everything on it.
你们想来抢吗 你们想开打吗
So you wanna do this? You wanna get down?
好 尽管上
Fine. Let's go.
你们敢动一下 我就消灭这整个岛
Move, and I'll obliterate this entire island.
还有岛上的一切
and everything on it.
是啊 也包括我们自己
Yeah. Including us.
你不觉得在我长篇大论之前
You don't think we should've spoken about this before.
我们应该先讨论一下吗
I just gave a whole speech?
嗯 你说得很好
Yeah, I liked the speech.
我只是觉得这样会更有用
I just thought this would be more effective.
你们听到了 别逼我用它
You heard me. Don't make me use it.
我们会不惜一切保护我们的世界
We'll do anything to protect our world.
我们也会
So will we.
这个宇宙里没有什么是杀不了的
Nothing in this universe is unkillable.
只要电压够强
With the proper voltage.
你们两个没事吧
Are you both all right?
没事 长官 好得不得了
Yes, sir. Never better.
- 长官 你是怎么找到我们的 - 凭经验
- Sir, how did you find us? - Experience.
又是瑞莎吗 H
Riza again, H?
你什么时候才会吸取教训
When are you going to learn?
我就知道你靠得住
I knew I could count on you.
你最后总能挺过来
That, in the end, you'd pull through.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
你也是 M
You too, M.
探员O对你有预感 她没看错人
Agent O had a feeling about you, and she was right.
宇宙总有办法
The universe has a way of leading you.
在恰当的时机
to where you're supposed to be…
将你引向应该去的地方
At the moment you're supposed to be there.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我们好好保管它 好吗
Let's keep this safe, shall we?
桑德 通知加贝边使馆
Saunder, inform the Jababian embassy,
武器在我们手里
we have the weapon.
M 对于见习探员来说
Quite the first assignment.
这个首次任务很惊险
for a probationary agent, M.
马拉喀什 空白之地 那不勒斯
Marrakesh, the Empty Quarter, Naples.
想象一下你正式加入我们后会有怎样的成就
Imagine what you will accomplish when you're one of us.
- 好的 长官 - 好好享受此刻 M
- Yes, sir. - Enjoy this moment, M.
不会持续太久
They never last.
我不知道你是怎么做到的 但是你总能成功
I don't know how you do it, but you just keep doing it.
是吗 我做什么了 C
Yeah? What's that, C?
拯救世界
Well, saving the world.
让它免于毁灭 而且是两次
from total destruction twice…
短短几年之间
in as many years.
我是说
I mean…
- 这也太巧了 - 这也太巧了
- what are the odds? - What are the odds?
黑衣人
MIB!
好了
Right.
- 失陪一下 - 好
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
觉得怎么样
How's it going?
- 你懂的 - 派对很酷 对吧
- You know. - Cool party, huh?
- 对 派对很棒 - 有事不对劲
- Yeah, great party. - Something is wrong.
对 我也这么想
Yeah. That's what I was thinking.
我告诉幻影双煞我们会不惜一切拯救我们的世界
I said to the Dyads we'd do anything to save our world.
他们说他们也会
They said that they would too.
他们说 为了蜂兽 他们必须拿到那件武器
Then they told us they needed the weapon for the Hive.
如果我们误解了他们的意思呢
What if we misunderstood what that meant?
也许他们需要用那件武器来对付蜂兽
Maybe they needed the weapon to use against the Hive.
拯救他们的世界
to save their world.
这可能意味着他们根本不是蜂兽
Which could mean they were never the Hive at all.
但是他们的DNA 突变
But the DNA, the mutations.
老大T给我们看了样本
High T showed us that sample.
好 我们看看
All right. Let's see.
我是探员H 请调出幻影双煞的法医报告
Agent H, bring up the Dyad forensic report.
（正在搜索）
（档案已删除）
谁有让案件档案消失的权限
Who has the authority to make a case file disappear?
跟我来
Come with me.
还有那不勒斯的事
And what about Naples?
他怎么知道我们在那里
How did he know we were there?
他在做分内事
He was doing his job.
分内事包括跟踪我们吗
Does his job include tracking us?
这是他送我的礼物 里面有芯片
He gave this to me as a gift. It has a chip inside it.
我们要看没收的加贝边武器
We need to see the confiscated Jababian weapon.
不行
Not possible.
不行 我是负责这个案子的高级探员
Not possible? I'm the senior agent on the case.
我说行就行 武器在哪
Let's make it possible. Where's the weapon?
我觉得他一直在追寻这件武器
I think he's been chasing it the entire time.
老大T就是内奸 一定是他
High T is the mole. He's gotta be.
谁派来的内奸 他要把武器拿去哪
A mole for who? Where would he take it?
巴黎
Paris.
我觉得是巴黎
My guess would be Paris.
我自始至终都觉得不对劲
I knew all along that something was off.
我以为他是在替你打掩护
I thought he was covering for you,
但是有问题的是他
but it turns out, it was him.
他是在掩盖自己的踪迹
He was hiding his own tracks.
肯定是有原因的 M 我们走
Gotta be an explanation. M, come on.
- 我跟你们一起去 - 不行 C
- I'm coming with you. - No, C.
别闹了 重点不在于你
Come on, now. This isn't about you.
我知道 我同意
I know. I agree.
听着 如果事实证明你说的是真的
Listen, if it turns out what you're saying is true.
然后消息传出去说T
and word gets out that T,
黑衣人史上最功勋卓著的探员是个叛徒
the most decorated agent in MIB history, is a traitor,
组织将永远无法恢复
the agency will never recover.
如果我们能阻止他 没必要让别人知道
If we stop him, no one ever has to know.
但如果你们不能阻止他呢 到时候怎么办
But what if you can't stop him? Then what?
到时候就告诉他们是我
Well, then tell them it was me.
告诉他们我是叛徒
Tell them I was the traitor.
相信我 组织会相信你的
Trust me, the agency will believe you.
你
You.
对了 出了那事儿
That's right. That happened.
这还差不多
That's what I'm talking about.
我来开车
I'm driving.
方向盘应该在这边的
That really should be here.
国家不同
Not in this country.
（引擎开关）
车里应该有个红色的大按钮
There should be a big red button somewhere.
对 按红色按钮
Yes! Press the red button.
找到了
Found it.
H 你得看看这个
H, you gotta see this.
C区的一个传送门已开启
A portal from Sector C has been activated.
蜂兽
The Hive.
我马上给你们派支援 完毕
I'm sending you backup. Out.
还记得我跟你说过 干这行就是撒谎吗
You remember when I told you we're in the lying business?
这是T招募我的时候说的话
T said that to me when he recruited me.
他说 「我们必须对全世界撒谎」
He said, "We have to lie to the world,
「也就是说我们绝不能对彼此撒谎」
which means we can never lie to each other."
我不相信他对我们撒谎了
I just don't believe that he has.
但你不能总是相信自己的直觉 H
But you can't always trust your gut, H.
有时候事情的本质和表象是相同的
Sometimes things are as they appear to be.
不 我们拯救了世界 老天啊
No, we saved the world, for God's sakes.
我们携手 仅用我们的智慧
Together, with nothing but our wits.
和我们的七系原子枪
and our Series-7 De-Atomizers.
我听说了
So I've heard.
- H - 怎么了
- H? - Yeah?
你能再为我讲一遍吗
Mind telling me one more time?
你们是如何打败蜂兽的
How'd you beat the Hive?
那是三年前的事
It was three years ago.
老大T和我去对峙蜂兽
High T and I went to face the Hive.
仅用我们的智慧和我们的七系原子枪 明白了吗
with nothing but our wits and our Series-7 De-Atomizers. Cool?
嗯 但你们是怎么做的
Yes, but how'd you do it?
等等 你在干什么
Wait. What are you doing?
- 我只是好奇 你们是怎么做的 - 我刚告诉你了
- I'm curious. How'd you do it? - I just told you.
- 但你什么都没说 - 我说了好几遍了
- You didn't, though. - I did a few times.
听着 老大T和我去对峙蜂兽
Okay, High T and I went up to face the Hive.
仅用我们的智慧和我们的七系原子枪…
with nothing but our wits and our Series-7 De-Atomizers…
我是不是…我是不是在重复自己
Am I… I'm repeating myself, aren't I?
- 一遍又一遍 - 一字不差
- Over and over. - Word for word.
嗯…我为什么会那么做
Yeah, um… Okay, why would I be doing that?
H 我觉得那晚你没有打败蜂兽
H, I don't think that you beat the Hive that night.
我觉得你被消除记忆了
I think you were neuralyzed.
你来道别了
You came to say goodbye.
还把可爱的M带来了
And you brought the lovely M.
可以真切的感受到这里的历史
You can really feel the history here.
埃菲尔发现虫洞
Eiffel discovering wormholes,
通往其他文明的通道
gangways to other civilizations,
第一批外星人移民
the First Alien Migration.
然后我们也在这里创造了历史 不是吗 H
And we made history here too, didn't we, H?
仅用我们的智慧和我们的七系原子枪
With just our wits and our Series-7 De-Atomizers.
不 我们没有
No. We didn't.
蜂兽想要银河系中最强大的武器
The Hive wanted the most powerful weapon in the galaxy,
所以你让万格斯把它交给黑衣人
so you had Vungus bring it to Men in Black.
等到武器到手 你就交给他们
You'd wait. When it came, you'd give it to them.
亲爱的孩子 你总是那么聪明
My dear boy, you were always a bright one…
但这是无法阻止的
but there's no stopping this.
没有这个武器碍事 所有的星球都会毁灭
With the weapon out of the way, every planet will fall,
从地球开始
starting with this one.
离开控制台
Step away from the controls.
你消除了我的记忆
You neuralyzed me.
让我成为了拯救世界的英雄
Made me a hero, the guy that saved the world.
活下来兜售谎言
Left alive to sell the lie.
他们想要这个
They wanted this.
你当时在场
You were there.
你一直就像是我的儿子
You were always like a son to me.
H
H?
你一直就像是我的儿子
You were always like a son to me.
他已经不是老大T了
That's not High T anymore.
你一直就像是
You were always like a son.
他的儿子
to him.
开枪 开枪
Shoot it! Shoot it!
女王陛下
My queen!
我来了
I'm coming!
我们怎么办 怎么办
What do we do? What do we do?
我要把它抢回来
I'm gonna get it back.
我知道他还没完全消失
I know he's still in there somewhere.
我知道你还没完全消失
I know you're in there somewhere!
是我 H
It's me, H.
记得吗 你想让我接任你的职位
Remember, you wanted me to take your place.
M
M!
宇宙的真谛
The truth of the universe.
我想知道宇宙的运作方式
I want to know how it all works.
宇宙总有办法
The universe has a way of leading you.
在恰当的时机
to where you're supposed to be.
将你引向应该去的地方
At the moment you're supposed to be there.
女王陛下
My queen!
我不要再失去一个女王了
I'm not losing another queen.
你说我就像是你的儿子
You said I was like a son to you.
你就像是我的父亲
You were like a father to me.
H
H.
恰当的时机
Right time…
恰当的地点
right place.
兵兵
Pawny?
- 怎么了 - 你的女王很满意你的服务
- Yeah? - You've served your queen well.
谢谢 夫人
Thank you, my lady.
这是我的荣幸
It was my honor.
她真的和传说中一样严厉吗
So is she as tough as they say?
简单概括 是的
In a word, yes.
- 你们居然没搞砸 - 是的 长官
- Well, you didn't screw up. - No, ma'am.
实话实说 过程是有点磕磕绊绊
Let's be honest, there were a few bumps along the way,
- 一开始有些摩擦… - 还是别说实话吧
- friction at the start… - Let's not be honest.
好吧 是的 我们没搞砸
Okay. No, we did not screw up.
你说伦敦可能有问题 但其实你早就知道
You said there may be a problem in London, but you knew.
我已经有一段时间不信任伦敦分部了
I hadn't trusted London branch for some time.
我一直不明白为什么
I never understood the reason why.
T为这个组织而活
T lived for this organization.
他是我们之中最出色的 我们会…
He was the very best we had to offer. He will be…
想念他的
missed.
欢迎加入马戏团 探员M
Welcome to the circus, Agent M.
你的试用期结束了
You are no longer probationary.
这就对了 我的任务完成了
Well, there you go. My work here is done, I…
- 你的试用期开始了 - 不好意思 你说什么
- You are. - I'm sorry, what?
你是伦敦分部的试用主管
Probationary head of London branch.
不好意思 试用主管
I'm sorry. Probationary head?
听起来我同时被升职和降职了
It sounds like I got promoted and demoted at the same time.
不是 适应一下
No. Try and cope.
几年前 在这一切之前 T跟我提起过
Several years ago, before all this, T mentioned to me.
一个年轻有位的外勤探员 他具有一定的
a young, up-and-coming field agent who had certain.
领导才能 可以这么说
leadership qualities, shall we say.
他错信你了吗
Was his faith in you misplaced?
没有 我只是觉得
No, I just think there are.
还有比我更有经验的探员
far more experienced agents than myself.
确实有 但我们的高级员工
Yeah, there are. But you have the full support.
还有探员C都全力支持你
of our senior staff and, by the way, Agent C.
是这样吗
Is that right?
- 就是说你接受职位了 - 是的
- Do I take it you accept? - Yes.
很好 我去跟上面的领导们谈
Good. I'll talk to the bosses upstairs.
你要清空你在伦敦分部的办公桌
You need to clear your London desk.
并在周一到黑衣人纽约分部报到
and report to MIB in New York on Monday.
纽约
New York.
谢谢你 探员O
Thank you, Agent O.
恭喜你 试用菜鸟
Congratulations, probie.
也恭喜你
Congratulations to you too.
你该去跟你的探员们说明情况了
You'll want to brief your agents.
跟我走走
Walk with me.
你想知道宇宙的运作方式
So you wanted to know how it all works.
现在你知道了
Now you do.
你一定也预料到了 探员M
And as you will no doubt have divined, Agent M,
这是有代价的
there's a price.
你好啊 你在干什么
Hey there. What are you doing?
我告诉O 回去之前
I told O I had to take care of.
我有几件事要处理
a couple things before I went back.
是吗 比如说偷我的车
Yeah? What, like stealing my car?
不 开你的车
No, like driving it.
至少这回你坐对边了
You're on the right side, at least.
我学得很快
I'm a quick study.
搭我回伦敦好吗
Give me a lift back to London?
公路旅行
Road trip.
起来 起来 起来
Up, up, up!
天啊 不需要这一出
Oh, God. Did not need that.
你能用那个洗脑的玩意闪我一下吗 拜托
Could you zap me with that forgetting thing, please?
你在这做什么 兵兵
What are you doing here, Pawny?
快点习惯见到我 小白脸
Get used to seeing me, pretty boy.
- 我是你的新保姆 - 他是我的新什么
- I'm your new babysitter. - He's my new what?
- 保姆 - 女王的命令
- Babysitter. - Queen's orders.
她说没有我 你这个可怜虫
She says the chance of your sorry ass.
活下来的几率为零
surviving without me: Zero.
我可没那么说 不是原话
Okay, I did not say that… exactly.
她说 「无限接近于零」
She said, "Slim to zero."
我四舍五入为零了
I rounded it down to zero.
因为感觉就是零
because I feel like it's zero.
当作是离别礼物吧
Consider it a parting gift.
拜托 我拯救了世界
Come on. I saved the world.
你不知道 因为你当时快被掐死了
You couldn't tell because you were getting choked on the floor.
- 我有选择权吗 - 没有
- Do I even have a choice? - No.
太好了 好了 那个红色的小按钮在哪呢
Yes! There we go. All right. Where's that little red button?
就在这儿
It's right here.
我还是不喜欢你
I still don't like you.
我喜欢这个选择
I love that option.
（引擎开关）
这是一台复杂的机器 所以要小心
This is a complicated piece of machinery, so be careful.
嗯 没问题
Yeah, got it.
我决定相信直觉
I'm gonna trust my gut.